Nichijou 72
It's true!
（相生祐子(あいおいゆうこ)）
ホント 大工(だいく)喫茶が―
The Daiku Café had a renovation!
リニューアルしたんだって
（長野原(ながのはら)みお）へえ
Here it is.
（みお）ホントだ
カフェになったんだ
Oh, wow.
They turned it into a café.
（玉村(たまむら)）いらっしゃいませ
Welcome!
I've been here before, so you can go ahead and order first, Mio-chan.
（祐子）私 前にも来てるから
みおちゃん　先に頼んでいいよ
Oh, really?
（みお）えっ そう？ じゃあ
Well then...
（祐子）エヘッ
ホワイトチョコレート
モカフラペチーノのグランデで
I'll take a grande white chocolate mocha Frappuccino.
Eh?
（みお）あっ あと追加で―
Also, I'd like a shot of espresso with caramel syrup,
キャラメルソース
ヘーゼルナッツシロップ―
hazelnut syrup, chocolate chips and extra whipped cream.
チョコレートチップ
エキストラホイップの―
エスプレッソショット１杯で
（祐子）死ねっ！
Die!
Wait! Yukko, where are you going!?
（みお）
ちょっ ゆっこ　どこ行くの？
Nakamura-sensei
The sleeping medicine didn't work on Shinonome.
（中村(なかむら)先生）睡眠薬は
東雲(しののめ)には効かなかった
That's where this comes in!
そこで これだ！
A mixture that increases the rate of oxidation,
酸化促進力を倍増させ
なおかつ 保険で―
Mr. Rust+!
and as added insurance, it also numbs the senses.
しびれ薬を配合させた
〝酸化君プラス！〞
Mr. Rust+!
If I get Shinonome to drink this,
これを東雲に飲ませ
一気に捕獲と しゃれ込むか
I'll easily capture and have my way with her.
ウフフフッ
捕獲したら どうしてやろうか？
What will I do after I capture her?
Well, this and that...
あんなことや こんなことや
2nd Science Room
Magnets: How do they work?
（大胡(おおご)）からし！
（祐子）たらし？
（東雲なの）
どど… どうしよう
What should I do?
Huh, we're using compasses today.
ふーん 今日
方位磁石 使うんだ
Nano-chan, did you get a compass too?
なのちゃん　方位磁石 渡った？
あっ はい！
Yes!
Everyone.
（みお）みんな！
（なの･祐子）うん？
Today's class is now a free-study session.
今日の授業 自習だって
（男子生徒）イエーイ！
（祐子）おお やった！ アハハッ
Oh! Yay!
（大胡）中村先生
また倒れたのかな？
Nakamura-sensei collapsed again?
Nakamura sure collapses a lot.
（祐子）よく倒れるなあ 中村
（なの）ハア
Nichijou 73
（立花(たちばな)みさと）
笹原(ささはら)―
Sasahara, why are you skipping clean-up duty again?
あんた 何また
掃除サボってんのよ
I cleaned up my own area.
（笹原幸治郎(こうじろう)）私は 自分の
持ち場は掃除したのだが
（みさと）あっ ホコリが
ド派手に残ってたわよ
You left behind a lot of dust!
（笹原）うん そうであったか
I see.
Hurry up and get back there.
（みさと）
早く持ち場に戻りなさい
By the way, how did you know I was on the roof?
（笹原）それより なぜ私が
屋上にいると分かったのだ？
Are you stupid!?
バッカじゃないの？
陽気な天気に誘われて―
I just came up here because the weather was so nice!
たまたま ふらりと
立ち寄っただけなんだから
I see.
そうか
Thanks for going through the trouble of checking my area, too.
わざわざ すまんな
私の持ち場まで見てもらって
（笹原）ふん？
Don't get the wrong idea!
（みさと）勘違いしないでよね
It's not like I'm doing it for you or anything!
べつに あんたのためなんかじゃ
ないんだからね！
ワオッ
Wow.
Crane Game
（なの･みお）わあ
Tokisadame
Nichijou 74
It's the weekend.
（祐子）休日 麻衣(まい)ちゃんと
隣町で待ち合わせ
I'm supposed to meet up with Mai-chan in the next town over.
Apparently I'll get free candy, so I'll bite!
タダでお菓子がもらえるらしいとの
ことなので 食いつく　フフフッ
Would you like some bread?
（おばちゃん）パン食べるかい？
（祐子）えっ？
Oh no, it's fine.
いや 大丈夫です
出るとき食べてきたんで
I ate on my way out!
（祐子）
ああ　犬は なんつーか
ルール違反じゃないか？
Aren't dogs, like, against the rules or something?
うん？ おっ よし
It's fine.
（おばあさん）結構です
（祐子）ひょおお！
I need to stand up because my stop is coming up soon!
おーと そろそろ着くから
立っとかないとな なんつって
Coming up next is Tokisadame Wholesale Town.
Tokisadame Wholesale Town.
Nice timing, announcer!
（祐子）
ナイス タイミン アナウンス
Tokisadame Wholesale Town.
（アナウンス）
時定問屋町 時定問屋町です
All right.
（祐子）よし さっさと降りよう
Let's just get off!
The exit is to your right.
To everyone on the train...
車内の皆さん さいなら
Farewell!
Well, well, well, I'll just say farewell from this side, then.
まあ まあ まあ　こっちから
おさらばするわけだしね
Endure it!
耐えろ 耐えろ　このくらいで
うろたえてどうする
There's no reason to get embarrassed over such a little thing!
（祐子）うわっ す… すみません
ちょっと あの 急いでたもので
Oh, pardon me!
I was in a bit of a hurry!
（祐子）いやああ！
ああ もう
Oh, I give up!
いいの いいの
もう二度と会わない子なんだし―
I'll never see her again.
This is the next town over.
隣町なんだし
誰も私のこと知らないんだしね
Nobody here knows me.
Don't worry about it!
気にしない 気にしない
Wait...
…て なんか ついてきてない？
Is she following me?
It must be my imagination.
気のせい 気のせい
I'm just thinking too much today.
今日は ちょっと
過敏になってるだけだ
She said there'd be a Daiku Burger as soon as I left the station...
…ていうか 駅降りたら
すぐ 大工バーガーがあるって
言ってたけど　どこだ？
Where is it?
The map Mai-chan gave me...
麻衣ちゃんから
もらった地図は―
Here
Daiku
Burger
...is a bit twisted.
Here
なんか グニャ グニャだし
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
It'd be quicker just to ask.
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
聞くが早いか　よしっ！
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
All right!
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Daiku
Burger
Here
Excuse me, where can I find the Daiku Bur-
あの すみません
大工バーガー どこか…
（祐子）あっ ちょ… ちょっと
さっきから なんで付いてくるの？
Hey!
Why have you been following me!?
There'll be copyright issues if you do that!
そういうのは あれだよ
著作権が どうとかするよ！
Daiku Burger is right over there.
大工バーガーなら ここの裏だよ
I'm meeting up with someone there, too.
私も そこで待ち合わせしてるから
よかったら案内するけど
If you want, I can show you the way.
Welcome!
（店員）いらっしゃいませ
Sorry, Nee-chan.
（みほし）悪い 姉ちゃん
部活で遅れた
I was held up in club.
（みさと）遅い！
You're late!
She really was meeting someone?
（祐子）ホントに
待ち合わせてたのか
Sorry for the wait.
（店員）お待たせしました
I guess Mai-chan isn't here yet.
（祐子）
まだ 麻衣ちゃんは来てないか
But seriously...
しかし 今日は厄日か
とんでもなく恥ずかしかったよ！
...today is just not my day!
It's been extremely embarrassing!
ああっ まあ いいか　隣町だし
Whatever.
I'm in a different town.
That's right!
そうだよ
ポジティブに捉えれば―
If you think positively about it,
it's good practise for life.
いい意味で
人生の予行演習になったじゃない
そうだよ　この恥ずかしさを
私は乗り越えてきたんだ！
That's right!
I'll overcome this embarrassment!
Now, I'll be able to overcome anything!
なんだって乗り越えられるよ！
Yukko.
（水上麻衣(みなかみまい)）ゆっこ
（祐子）んん
Sorry for the wait.
（麻衣）お待たせ
Mai-chan!
麻衣ちゃーん！
Could that possibly be...
それ もしかして…
Trick or Treat.
（麻衣）トリック オア トリート
If it's come to this, then there's no helping it.
（祐子）
こうなったら しょうがない
I'll get my  treat.
お菓子をもらいに―
まいる！
Trick or Treat.
（祐子）トリック オア トリート
（みほし）クククククッ
（みさと）ハロウィン 先週だぞ
Are they dressing up for Halloween?
Crows are like this!
When you absolutely must pass by a menacing crow,
（カラス）カー カー カー
（祐子）うわっ ガア ガア
（祐子）ガア ガア
（カラス）カー カー カー
it is extremely important not to lose eye contact.
Shinonome Institute
Sleep
（はかせ）ん…
なんか あんまり眠くない
I really can't fall asleep.
They say if you count sheep jumping over a fence,
（阪本(さかもと)）
羊が柵を跳び越えるのを数えれば
寝られるっていうぞ
you can fall asleep.
All right, I'll try it.
分かった やってみる
One sheep...
羊が１匹　グーッ
She fell asleep with one sheep!
（阪本）１匹で寝よった！
Professor, that's amazing!
はかせ　すごい 私も
I'll try, too!
One shee-
羊が… プー
The sheep... didn't even make it over.
（阪本）羊 跳び越さんかった
Volunteer Spirit
It's finished.
出来たよ
Thanks.
ありがとう
さすが 姉ちゃん
As expected of Nee-chan!
ねえ こういうのって
笹原さんが教えてくれるの？
Does Sasahara-san teach you this kind of thing?
どっ どうして―
Why does he have to teach me everything?
あいつに 手取り 足取り
教えてもらわなきゃならないのよ
But don't you guys get along really well?
だって 仲いいでしょ？
全然よ 全然
全然というか 全然なんだから！
Not at all! Not at all.
I mean, not at all!
Nee-chan, calm down.
（みほし）姉ちゃん 落ち着いて
Still, you ironed his handkerchief earlier.
でも この前 ハンカチに
アイロン当ててたじゃん
あっ あれは たまたま
道で拾ったゴミなんだってば
That was just garbage I found on the street.
Eh?
（みほし）ええ？
笹原さんのだからでしょ？
It was Sasahara-san's, wasn't it?
うっ　だ… だから
違うって言ってるでしょ
I'm telling you, that's not what happened.
I was just exercising my arms,
あれは 腕の筋トレを
しようとしてたら―
and there happened to be an iron there.
ちょうど あの
アイロンがあって―
Also, there happened to be a handkerchief under it.
たまたま その下に
あのハンカチがあっただけ
みたいな…
Something like that...
Something like that!
みたいな なんだから！
（みほし）わ… 分かりやし
She's so easy to read...
But Nee-chan, you looked so happy when you were ironing it.
（みほし）でも 姉ちゃん
アイロンかけてるとき
あんな うれしそうだったじゃん
バ… バカ言ってんじゃないわよ
That's stupid!
At that moment...
あのときは… あのときは！
At that moment, the Earth was just passing through the Photon Belt!
地球がフォトンベルトに
入ってただけなんだけど！
So, listen to this!
（女子高生１）
ねえ 聞いて　昨日さ
What?
（女子高生２）なに なに？
I talked to Ono-kun yesterday!
（女子高生１）
私 大野(おおの)君と しゃべっちゃった
（女子高生２）ええっ いいなあ
You're so lucky!
On a train for two hours.
（女性）
電車で２時間　バスで１時間
On a bus for one.
From the tough city,
都会の雑踏を離れ―
I have come to this remote S-town.
私は この片田舎のＳ町に
やってきた
Even though I didn't believe I would ever find it again,
それというのも―
もう見つかることは
一生ないだろうと思いながらも―
I couldn't give up, and I've continued to search for that book.
あきらめきれず ずっと前から
探し続けていた一冊の本が―
That book, which is said to be a myth,
灰色だった私の少女時代を
彩ってくれた―
gave colour to my grey childhood days.
幻と言われた あの本が―
It is in this library.
この図書館に入ったから
I will be able to read that book in this age.
この時代に あの本が読める
I am thankful that I happened to meet the donor.
寄贈された方との巡り合わせに
感謝し その書を手に取る
Because of that, I got my hands on it.
Tones of a
Clear Autumn
With my heart beating fast,
高鳴る鼓動を抑えつつ 私は…
I...
...slowly opened my prize.
ゆっくりと書を開いた
Love-Like
All right, time's almost up.
（先生）はーい
そろそろ時間だから―
Everyone, make sure you wrote your name.
みんな　名前を書いてるか
確認してね
Ten.
じゅう きゅう はち
Nine.
Eight.
Sev-
-en.
ろーく ごーお
Six.
Five.
Four.
よーん　さーん
Three.
Two.
にーい
One.
（先生）いーち
（女の子）はあ
ウフッ　ゼロ
Zero.
All right, pass them forward.
はーい じゃあ
後ろから回してください
Nichijou 75
ハロウィンは
とっくに終わってますよ
Halloween was a while back.
（女子高生１）フウ フウ
This coffee isn't very coffee-like.
この コーヒー あんまり
コーヒー コーヒーしてない
Huh? It's not "coffee-like"?
（女子高生２）ええっ？
コーヒー コーヒーしてない？
What does that mean?
何言ってんの？
I don't really know how to explain it,
あっ 自分でも
よく分かんないんだけど―
but it's not really... coffee-like.
なんていうか
コーヒー コーヒーしてないんだよ
Just take a sip.
いいから ちょっと飲んでみ
ほれ ほれ
Come on.
Really, what does it mean to be not coffee-like?
まったく コーヒー コーヒー
してないって 何なのよ
（女子高生２）あっ！
It's not coffee-like.
コーヒー コーヒーしてない
（なの･はかせ）チュン チュン
（はかせ）ウウ ピョン
（なの）ピョン
（はかせ）ピョン
（はかせ）ウウ ポン
（はかせ･なの）ばあ！
Shinonome Institute
Everyone!
Nichijou 76
（はかせ）みんな！
ついに 完成しました
It's finally finished!
Meet Biscuit #2.
ビスケット２号です
I'm Biscuit #2.
（ビスケット２号）
ビスケット２号です
Oh, I remember him.
（なの）ああ こないだの
（阪本）んん？
Such a bland reaction!
（ビスケット２号）
リアクション 薄っ
Hey, take a closer look!
ちょっと ちゃんと
見てほしいんだけど
But I already saw him before.
でも この前も見ましたし
#1 and #2 are different!
１号と２号は違うんだけど
もっと もーっと すごいんだけど
He's much more amazing!
My name is Biscuit #2.
（ビスケット２号）
僕の名前はビスケット２号
I'm a biscuit robot created by Professor Shinonome.
東雲はかせに作られた
ビスケットロボットだ
As the name implies,
その名のとおり
動力源はビスケット
my power source is biscuits.
I operate on the power of biscuits.
ビスケットで
僕は 稼働するんだ
Professor, it's about time for a biscuit.
はかせ そろそろ
ビスケットのほうを
Eh?
ええ これ
最後の１個なんだけど
But this is the last one...
（ビスケット２号）ええ
Biscuit #2's special skill is speed-reading.
ビスケット２号の特技は
速読です どうぞ！
Go ahead.
完了です
Finished!
（ビスケット２号･はかせ）
はいっ！
There!
Why aren't you amazed?
なんでビックリしないの？
Well, I can read fast, too.
あっ いやあ
私も速く読めますし
Then why do you always read so slowly?
（はかせ）じゃあ なんで
いつもノソノソ読んでるの？
I think that this way...
なんか こっちのほうが
普通の人っぽいかなと思って
...makes me more like a normal person.
（はかせ）ゴニョ ゴニョ ゴニョ
（ビスケット２号）うん ふんふん
フアア
What's wrong, Biscuit #2?
いったい どうしたの？
ビスケット２号
I get sleepy when I read a lot of words in a book.
本は 文字が いっぱいあると
眠くなっちゃいますね
（はかせ）プププ
それ ちょっと普通だけど
That's pretty normal.
（はかせ）うわ！
（なの）わあっ
Why won't you say it's amazing?
なんで すごいって言わないの？
はかせは いっぱい すごいのに
I'm really amazing!
What?
何だ そんなことで
怒ってたんですか
You're mad about something small like that?
It's not something small!
（はかせ）
そんなことじゃないもん
But you were already amazing.
だったら はかせは―
最初から すごいじゃないですか
Is that so?
そうだった はかせ
ちょっと間違えちゃったかも
Maybe I made a bit of a mistake.
（なの）べつに
間違えてはないと思いますけど
I don't really think you made a mistake.
Hey, hey.
（はかせ）ねえねえ
はかせ どんくらい すごい？
How amazing am I?
Um, how about as much as the Chichibu Mountain Range?
えーと
秩父連山くらいですかね？
（はかせ）
ええ それじゃ分かんない
I don't know how much that is!
Um, then how about the Nullarbor Plain?
（なの）えーと じゃあ
ナラボー平原とかですかね？
Eh? Why not something bigger?
（はかせ）ええ
もっと大きいのがいい
（なの）
じゃあ クジラとかですか？
Then, how about a whale?
Oh, that might be good.
（はかせ）あっ それかもしれない
Whales are big, aren't they?
（なの）
クジラは大きいですからね
Yeah, they are!
（はかせ）ですからね
Word Of The Day
It's not that it's fine like that,
and it's not that it's fine like this,
it's fine like that.
What are you doing?
（兵士Ａ）お前　何やるんだ？
I'm doing sugoroku.
TL Note: Japanese backgammon.
（兵士Ｂ）俺 すごろく
What are you doing?
（兵士３番）お前　何やんの？
I have a quiz.
（兵士６番）俺はクイズだ
A quiz is peaceful and fun!
クイズなら 和気あいあいと
楽しめるだろ？
Winning money by making the princess happy...
（兵士52番）しっかし
姫を喜ばせたら金一封って―
...seems like an interesting form of recreation.
面白そうな
レクリエーションだよな？
You gotta have something fun like this every now and then.
（兵士16番）たまには
こういう楽しみもなくっちゃ―
やってられんでしょう
Right?
（兵士８番）だあなっ
（兵士たち）おお！
The ball was in this one, right?
（兵士66番）先ほど
ボールは こちらに入れましたが
It's actually in here.
（兵士66番）実は こちらです
Nice going, number 66.
（兵士たち）おお！
（兵士８番）やるなあ 66番
I can't believe you had that kind of skill.
（兵士16番）お前に
そんな特技が あったなんてなあ
えへへっ 実は―
I'm actually aiming to be an official magician for the empire.
こっそり王室の専属マジシャン
目指してんだ
If that happens, you'll have a nice job.
そうなれば 安泰だもんなあ
まあな
Yeah.
（兵士25番）
おお 俺も燃えてきたぜえ
I'm fired up now, too!
I'll definitely win the prize money!
（兵士43番）
絶対 金一封 取ってやる！
Hey, it's time.
（おつき）おいっ！ 時間だぞ
Nichijou 77
Be quiet.
（おつき）
静かに！ では さっき配った
クジの番号順に始めろ
Attendant
Now then,
proceed in the order of the number you received.
Number one, please step forward.
１番目の者　前へ
私からです
I'm first.
Oh, number 66 is first?
（兵士16番）
おお いきなり66番からかあ
こりゃ 早速 金一封だなあ
The money will be won right away.
An imperial magician, huh?
（兵士８番）専属マジシャンか
フッ 夢をつかめよ 66番
Seize your dream, number 66.
（兵士たち）おっ すげ
Now, where is the ball?
さあ ボールは
どこにあるでしょうか？ えっ？
ああ！ 私を専属マジシャンに
I want to be an imperial magician!
Next.
（スターラ姫）次
Number two, step forward!
クジ番号２番　前へ
It's time.
（兵士４番）ついに来た
俺の名を 世界に知らしめるとき
Time for my name to be known by the world!
I'll turn this into a chance.
ピンチをチャンスに変えてやらあ
That's...
（兵士56番）あれって
Number 4, the comedian.
（兵士８番）ユーモアの４番
He can do it.
あいつの お笑いなら
いけるんじゃないか？
I, number 4, shall be going.
（兵士４番）４番
いかせていただきます
ばああ！
Next.
次
No way. Number 4, too?
（兵士８番）まさか ４番まで
（おつき）クジ番号３番 前に
Hey, are you okay?
（兵士８番）おい 大丈夫か？
（兵士６番）お… 俺だ
It's me.
え？ お前　さっきクイズって
But you said...
...you had a quiz.
I can't believe it turned out like this.
（兵士６番）まいった
こんなことになるなんて
But my only skill is with quizzes.
しかし 俺の とりえといったら
クイズしかないし―
I must assure that the princess gets it correct.
ここは１つ 絶対に
姫に正解してもらわねば
It's okay.
（兵士６番）大丈夫だ
I won't let myself fail.
（兵士６番）ミスは許されない
I should probably make it a simple one.
恐ろしく簡単な
問題にしなくては
I, number 6, will give a quiz!
ろ… ６番
クイズで いかせていただきます
What kind of bread can you not eat?
パ… パンはパンでも
食べられないパンは なーんだ！
ハア ハア ハア
あはっ 答えは２択です
１番フライパン　２番メロンパン
Oh, it's multiple choice!
A) Frying pan.
B) Melon bread.
さあ 何番？
Now, which is the answer?!
（兵士たち）あ… あいつ
What?
分からん
I don't know.
せ… 正解でございます！
That is correct!
I regret everything!
（兵士６番）
我が人生に 一片の
悔いありい！
（兵士52番）あああ 終わりだ
It's over.
Even the quiz master was expelled.
（兵士16番）
クイズマスターまで
逝っちまいやがった
Next.
（スラータ姫）次！
I, number 7, will recite all the cities that have hosted the Olympics!
（兵士７番）
な… ７番 オリンピックの開催地を
全部 言わせていただきます
（スラータ姫）フワア
（兵士７番）待って！
（兵士７番）ああ！
I will never forget your courage, number 7.
（兵士８番）お前の
勇気だけは忘れないぞ ７番
What's wrong?
どうした？ 誰か 姫を
楽しませられる者はいないのか？
Is there no one who can please the princess?
（兵士８番）ど… どうすんだ？
What should I do?
I intended to do a cheer...
俺なんか チアガール
やるつもりだったのに
You fool!
（兵士０番）
バカ野郎！ 俺なんか
ケツで割り箸 折るんだぞ
I was going to break chopsticks with my ass!
I was going to play a bamboo screen!
（兵士39番）
俺は 南京玉すだれだ！
I was going to chop up a cabbage!
（兵士91番）
俺なんかキャベツの千切りだぜ
We're all going to be erased.
（兵士８番）
俺たち全員 消されるぞ
Hey, hey.
（兵士13番）おい おい
俺を忘れてもらっちゃ困るぜ
I hope you're not forgetting about me.
（兵士15番）お… お前は！
You're...
From that comedic stance,
その ひょうきんっぷりから―
it's the comedian that no one in the comic world can surpass:
ひょうきん界わいでは
右に出る者がいない ひょうきん者
Comedian 13!
ひょうきん13(サーティン)！
I'm gonna go visit the brink of death...
（兵士13番）
俺が起死回生の１発をお見舞いして
場の空気を変えてやるぜ　フンッ
...and change the atmosphere.
（兵士15番）待て 13
それは あまりにも危険すぎる！
Wait, 13!
That's far too dangerous!
Do you think I'm simply going to do the "swan lake" dance?
俺が ただ単に 白鳥の湖を
舞うだけだと思うかい？
（兵士たち）だあっ！
Well, watch closely.
（兵士13番）まあ 見てな
I'll teach you about true comed-
本当の ひょうきんてやつを
俺が教え…
Watch me!
やるぜえ！
Comedian 13!
（兵士15番）
ひょうきん 13！
あれ？
Why me, too?!
なぜ俺まで！
Next. Number five.
（おつき）次 ５番
How long are you going to make us wait?
いつまで待たせる気だ
早く出てこい！
Hurry up!
Who is it?
（兵士５番）誰だ？
（兵士Ａ）５番のやつ 誰だ？
Who the heck is number five?
Is it you?
（兵士０番）お前か？
（兵士５番）違う
No!
That's the number on my hat!
（兵士５番）これは帽子の番号だ！
（兵士Ｂ）誰だ？ 誰だ？
（兵士８番）ん？ ああ
Hey...
お… おい　５番って お前じゃ？
Number five is you-
（兵士11番）ヘヘヘッ あああ
He's finished!
（兵士たち）終わった
Hey, number five!
おい ５番　いいかげんに出てこい
いったい どいつだ？
Get out here!
What's wrong?
（兵士11番）やっ や…
はい はい はい
（兵士たち）え？ やっぱり！
And still!
Next.
次　誰でもいいから やれ
I don't care who.
Someone go.
（兵士Ａ）もう
No matter what we do, it's...
（兵士Ｂ）どう あがいても
（兵士Ｃ）こりゃあ
...hopeless!
（兵士たち）ダメだ
（兵士８番）
うはっ ハア ハアハア
うんっ ハア…
No matter how many lives you have, it's not enough for that!
あんなんじゃ 命がいくつあっても
足りやしねえぜ
I won't participate in such a selfish kind of recreation!
あんな わがままな
レクリエーションに―
つきあって られっかあ！
ぬわっ
I'll go stand in the hall!
廊下に立ってます！
I'm a sweet grande white chocolate mocha Frappuccino...
（コーヒー店のドリンク）
甘ーい ひとときを お届けするー
キャラメルソース
ヘーゼルナッツシロップ―
...with a shot of espresso and caramel syrup, hazelnut syrup,
チョコレートチップ
エクストラホイップの―
エスプレッソショットを
１杯追加した―
chocolate chips and extra whipped cream.
ホワイトチョコレート
フラペチーノのグランデでーす
Next time on Nichijou: Episode 19.
次回の「日常」は
第19話　お楽しみに
Narration:     Aikawa Rikako
Look forward to it!